<RECIPE>
  <TITLE>Chicken Tikka Masala</TITLE>
  <IMAGE>tikka_masala.jpg</IMAGE>
  <CATEGORY>Indian</CATEGORY>
  <SERVINGS>4</SERVINGS>
  <TIME>50 minutes</TIME>
  <INGREDIENTS>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>1 cup/240g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Full-fat yogurt</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>2 tsp</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Kosher salt</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>2.25 tbsp/20g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Garam masala</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>2 tsp/6g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Paprika</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>5</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Garlic cloves (finely chopped)</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>2x 2 inch knobs</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Ginger (grated)</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>900g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Chicken thighs (diced)</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>1</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Onion (thinly sliced)</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>1 tsp/3g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Cayenne powder</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>425g</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Can of crushed tomatoes</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <INGREDIENT>
      <QUANTITY>1 cup</QUANTITY>
      <NAME>Heavy cream</NAME>
    </INGREDIENT>
    <EXTRA>Sugar</EXTRA>
    <EXTRA>Coriander</EXTRA>
    <EXTRA>Rice</EXTRA>
  </INGREDIENTS>
  <STEPS>
    <STEP>In a medium-sized bowl, add yogurt, salt, 1.25tsp/11g garam masala, 1 tsp/3g paprika, garlic, and 1 of the knobs of ginger; whisk to combine. Next, add chicken to your bowl, toss to coat thoroughly, and marinate for 10 minutes or overnight in the fridge.</STEP>
    <STEP>Set a pan over medium-high heat, and add enough oil to coat the bottom of the pan. Once hot and nearly smoking, add all your chicken in batches and sear for 2 - 3 minutes per side until nicely browned on all edges.</STEP>
    <STEP>Remove chicken, add additional oil if needed, and lower the heat to medium. Add onion, ginger, and garlic. Season lightly with salt, and saute for 3 - 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until softened. Next, add paprika, cayenne, garam masala, and sugar; saute until fragrant, about 30 seconds.</STEP>
    <STEP>Add crushed tomatoes, stir and reduce for 5 minutes. Optionally, pour into a blender and blend on high speed until as smooth as possible. Place back in the pot, reduce the heat to low, add all your chicken, and simmer, stirring occasionally, for 10 minutes or until the chicken is thoroughly cooked and the sauce is reduced.</STEP>
    <STEP>Stir in heavy cream and reduce for 7 - 8 more minutes or until the sauce is thick and velvety—adjust salt levels if necessary. Serve immediately with steamed white rice. Optionally garnish with coriander.</STEP>
  </STEPS>
</RECIPE>
